Guide to the Voices of Brooklyn oral histories 2008.031
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Arts and entertainment, 2006-; 2008.031.1
  - Weiner, Gina Ingoglia, 2014 April 21; 2008.031.1.011
    Born in Philadelphia in 1938, Gina Ingoglia Weiner grew up in New York City and Long Island. She moved to the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights in 1968 and, with her husband Earl Weiner, lived in a brownstone they bought in 1979. She attended Dickinson College for her undergraduate degree, mastered in Publishing at New York University and attained a bachelor's degree in landscape architecture at Rutgers University. Weiner wrote over eighty children's books and also wrote and illustrated publications on nature and gardening. In her private practice, she designed gardens and landscapes for residences. Weiner served on several boards and committees in the New York City cultural community, including that of Brooklyn Historical Society. Gina Ingoglia Weiner died in March, 2015.
    In the interview, Gina Ingoglia Weiner talks about her family and her family's history as well as her career as a children's books writer and illustrator. She tells her parents' stories; her mother, Denis Gerdes spent some formative years in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn, and her father, Frank Ingoglia was born in Brooklyn and grew up in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn and later New Jersey. Weiner relates the various moves of the couple; New York City, then Philadelphia, and later New Hyde Park, Long Island, and traces their jobs and careers. She also goes further into her family background, covering her grandparents and a great grandmother. Weiner talks about her education, and some of her children's books, as well as meeting her husband Earl when they were both attending Dickinson College, and their decision to move to Brooklyn Heights in 1968. She discusses her career moves, work highlights, and creative process; taking note of her work for the Golden Books imprint, stories inspired by Disney properties, and Brooklyn Botanic Garden publications. In closing, she describes what volunteering means to her and welcomes a future opportunity to discuss her board service and experiences at Brooklyn Historical Society. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Authors, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Children's books; Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Illustration of books; Long Island (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.); Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Publishers and publishing |z New York (State) |z New York; Women |x Education (Higher) |z New York (State) |z New York; Brooklyn Botanic Garden
  - Weston, Randy and Cliff Smalls, 2006 October 11; 2008.031.1.012
- Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Business and industry, 2008-; 2008.031.2
  This series includes oral histories collected through several projects undertaken by the Brooklyn Historical Society beginning in 2008. The assembled series took shape in 2008 under the project title "Brooklyn History Makers." The ongoing oral history series, retitled in 2016, features a range of narrators: store managers, small business owners, bakers, and restaurateurs among them, who describe the changes they have observed in their neighborhoods over decades.
  - Baker, Michael, 2010 June 25; 2008.031.2.001
    Michael Baker was born in Canada in 1959 and came to New York City to open the IKEA home furnishings store in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn. As a college student, he had worked in retail. Baker went on to learn more in a management program and began a career with home furnishings retailers. After he was hired on by IKEA, he helped the company expand globally, until he was asked to not only oversee the construction of a store in Canada, but stay on as store manager. In the mid-2000s, he did the same for IKEA Brooklyn. As of the 2010 interview, he and his family were residing in the Bay Ridge neighborhood of Brooklyn; an area they deemed to have the best schools.
    In this interview, Michael Baker briefly discusses growing up in Canada and how he got involved in retail store management. He talks in great detail about opening the IKEA in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn; from negotiations with the City, the Metropolitan Transportation Authority, and the local community boards to finding bedrock for driving in anchor piles, and how the home furnishings store wanted to maintain the site's waterfront history. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Commerce; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 21st century; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs; Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Canada; Docks |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Employees |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Environmental impact analysis |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Furniture industry and trade |z New York (State) |z New York; Local transit -- New York (State) -- Kings County; New York (N.Y.); Red Hook (New York, N.Y.); Retail trade |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Shipyards |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History; Waterfronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Zoning -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Baker, Michael; Deserio, Pino; Ikea (Firm); Todd Shipyards Corporation. Brooklyn Division
  - Caputo, James and John, 2010 April 8; 2008.031.2.002
    Born in 1941 in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn to a father from Brooklyn and a mother from Rome, Italy, John Caputo was the fourth generation to run a Caputo Bakery in Brooklyn. His son, James Caputo was born in 1971. Both Caputos enjoyed childhoods spent at the bakery shop. After being urged by his father to look into a less-physically demanding career, James studied finance and went to work on Wall Street for ten years. The son came back to the family business, and the two worked side by side. At the time of this 2010 interview, John Caputo was semi-retired.
    In the interview, John and James Caputo talk about generations of the Caputo family and the business history of their co-owned Caputo Bakery in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn. John describes the sequence of locations for Caputo's; one near Union and Hicks Streets that was shuttered because of Brooklyn-Queens Expressway construction in the 1940s, another at 332 Court Street, and the present one that faces that old address. John recalls the businesses and scenery of his youth. The two discuss how each came into the business and how modern life has eased the demands of long hours and baking business inefficiencies. The two identify evolving styles and quality of bread in the overall market and at Caputo's. James reflects on appreciating the bakery in his youth, achieving a career in finance, and returning to work with his father at the bakery. They go over their changing clientele, the staffing of a bakery, and different technologies used in the bakery's different ovens through the years. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan and Margaret Fraser.
    Bakery employees |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Bakeries |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Baking; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.); Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County
  - Deserio, Pino, 2010 July 28; 2008.031.2.003
    Biographical note
    Pino (Joseph) Deserio was born in Mola De Bari, Italy in 1952. He came to the United States in 1970 with his father via ship, and eventually his mother and six siblings joined them. As soon as he turned eighteen, he started working as an electrician's helper at Todd Shipyards in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn. He worked there until Todd Shipyards closed and sold the land to IKEA in 2005. Along with the rest of his family, Deserio has lived in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn since the 1970s. He was married and raised two daughters there. At the time of the 2010 interview, Deserio was working as the facilities manager at IKEA in Red Hook on the same site as his previous job with Todd Shipyards.
    In this interview, Pino Deserio describes his life in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn and the Italian American community's establishments there; including the Van Westerhout Mola Sport Club, established by those originally from Mola Di Bari, Italy, and the St. Stephen Roman Catholic Church. He talks about his family, immigration, and changes in the neighborhood, and also changes back in Italy, which he visits every year. Deserio gives a thorough description of all the steps necessary for getting a ship into a graving dock, a difficult process that was his responsibility by the time Todd Shipyards closed. Deserio also discusses the loss of his wife to breast cancer when she was only forty-five years old and shares his hopes for his two daughters. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs; Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.); Docks |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Italian Americans |x Social life and customs; Italy; Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Navy-yards and naval stations |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Red Hook (New York, N.Y.); Shipping |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Shipyards |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Waterfronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Deserio, Pino; New York Naval Shipyard; Todd Shipyards Corporation. Brooklyn Division
  - Sahadi, Charles, 2016 April 4; 2008.031.2.004; Sahadi, Charles Wade
    Charles Wade Sahadi (1944- ) was born in Brooklyn, New York to Lebanese parents in 1944. Sahadi was raised on a racially diverse block in Bay Ridge, Brooklyn with two younger brothers. His family attended an Antiochian Orthodox Christian church in downtown Brooklyn until 1951 when Saint Mary's Antiochian Orthodox Church was built in Bay Ridge. His father, Wade Sahadi, bought 187 Atlantic Avenue in 1946 and moved his business, Sahadi Importing Company, into the building in 1948. When Sahadi was a teenage, he would help work at the family store on Saturdays. Sahadi attended PS 104 and Fort Hamilton High School before spending two years at Pace College for an accounting degree. Sahadi left college to help assist his father with the family business after two years at Pace College. He got married to his wife, Audrey, and started working at the family business full-time in 1964. Sahadi and Audrey have three children, two of whom work in the family business. Upon the death of his father in 1967, Sahadi took over running Sahadi Importing Company. He stepped down from running the business in 2016.
    During his interview, Charles Wade Sahadi (1944- ) discusses growing up in Bay Ridge, Brooklyn; the growth and expansion of Sahadi's; other businesses on Atlantic Avenue and changes to the neighborhood; the Atlantic Avenue Merchants' Association and the development of the street festival "Atlantic Antic – it's gigantic!" Sahadi also recalls visiting Lebanon for the first time, his experiences as a business leader and community member after the September 11 terrorist attacks, the changes in demand for Middle Eastern food items as non-Middle Eastern people became more aware of Middle Eastern foods. Interview conducted by Zaheer Ali.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Atlantic Avenue (New York, N.Y.); Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y); Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Lebanon; Business enterprises; Community development, Urban |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Cooking, Middle Eastern; Grocery trade; Lebanese Americans; Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 |v Personal narratives; Trading companies; Sahadi Importing Company
  - Windt, Robert, 2009 January 16; 2008.031.2.007
    Robert "Bob" Windt was born in Manhattan, but moved with his family at the age of four to the upper-middle class Borough Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. Windt's father, a first-generation American of Austro-Hungarian Jewish heritage, gave up his half-partner position in a large manufacturing concern to spend more time with his children before founding the successful Fisk jewelry business. The elder Windt died in 1932, when his son was just twelve years old; the death had a lasting impact on the young Windt. Windt attended P.S. 180, Montauk Junior High School, and graduated from New Utrecht High School in 1938. In anticipation of the United States' entry to World War II, in 1940 Windt joined the Army, where he specialized in carburation and was a B-29 Bomber instructor; he was saved from deployment by the dropping of the atomic bomb. After the war's conclusion, Windt embarked on a successful career in show-business publicity, working with and for Dumont Laboratories, CBS, Pepsi Cola, and Rheingold Brewing Company before launching his own firm, whose major contract was with Fairchild Publications. Robert Windt passed away in October of 2014.
    In this wide-ranging interview, Robert "Bob" Windt shares his life's history, starting with his family's ancestral history and ending with his retirement. He describes his Austro-Hungarian Jewish heritage and his family's capture of the American dream; and racial relations in the Jewish-Italian Borough Park neighborhood of his youth. He discusses his sadness at his father's early passing; and his early experiences with the Jewish religion. Windt describes his young adulthood, including two years spent "piddling around," which led to his decision to preemptively join the Army as a flight engineer. He describes his experiences in Army training, including Officer's training at the Boca Raton Club, his commission as a lieutenant, and his disappointment over not being deployed. Windt details his start in publicity for the show business industry, selling radios and television sets for CBS-Columbia, and frequently references screen stars of the 1940s and 1950s, including Sammy Kaye, Perry Como, Joan Crawford, Arthur Godfrey, and others. Windt tells of subsequent years spent at Pepsi Cola and Rheingold Beer, including tales of insider business drama, proxy wars, ego battles, and bitter competition. He discusses the launch of his own firm, where his major contract was with Fairchild Publications. At the interview's conclusion, Windt discusses his love of baseball and his passionate distaste for the abuse of eminent domain, even when invoked for the construction of sports arenas. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Borough Park (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z New York; Entertainers |z United States; Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Public relations; Religion |z New York (State) |z Kings County; World War, 1939-1945; Brooklyn Dodgers (Baseball team)
- Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Civic leaders, 2006-; 2008.031.3
  - Hamm, Charles, 2006 November 13; 2008.031.3.001
  - Hamm, Charles, 2006 November 14; 2008.031.3.002
  - MacCrate, Robert, 2007 March 15; 2008.031.3.003
    Robert MacCrate was born in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1921. He attended high school at Brooklyn Friends School, and then moved on to Haverford College. After his time at Haverford, he had a brief stint in the Navy serving in the Pacific theater of World War II, and then attended Harvard Law School, where he met his wife, then Constance Trapp. From Harvard, he got a job at Sullivan & Cromwell in New York, and moved to Long Island. Beginning in 1958 he worked as counsel to the Governor of New York (Nelson Rockefeller) until 1962. During this time he was heavily involved in the expansion of the State University of New York system. He chaired the American Bar Association Task Force on Law Schools and the Profession, which in 1992 issued what is popularly known today as "The MacCrate Report," which discussed the state of legal education in the United States and stressed the importance of practical experience over purely theoretical learning. It has had a large impact on the way law is taught in the U.S. and abroad. He was living on Long Island with his wife when the interview occurred in 2007. Robert and Constance MacCrate both died in 2016, and were survived by three children. Additional biographical details can be found in notes of other interviews with MacCrate.
    In this first of four interviews, Robert MacCrate recollects the life of his grandparents and for a long period, tells the life-story of his father, who was a Brooklyn based lawyer and later, congressman and federal judge. He moves into a discussion of his own time in college and recounts the ways in which his life has been intertwined with a friend from Haverford. MacCrate describes his first job at the Sullivan & Cromwell law firm and his move back to New York City from Harvard in Boston. He also mentions that in 1959 he became the general counsel to the Governor of New York. MacCrate discusses what is popularly—although unfairly, according to him—called "The MacCrate Report," which was released by The American Bar Association Task Force on Law Schools and the Profession (which he chaired). Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History; Education, Higher |z New York (State); Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Governors |z New York (State); Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Law firms |z New York (State) |z New York; Law reports, digests, etc. |z New York (State); Lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York; Long Island (N.Y.); New York (State) |x Politics and government; Quakers |z New York (State) |z Kings County
  - MacCrate, Robert, 2007 March 21; 2008.031.3.004
    Robert MacCrate was born in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1921. After attending Harvard Law School, he got a job at Sullivan and Cromwell law firm in New York, and moved to Long Island. Beginning in 1958 he worked as counsel to Governor Rockefeller until 1962. During this time he was heavily involved in the expansion of the State University of New York system, as well as engineering the modernization of state courts and redrawing a number of congressional district borders in New York City in order to increase representation for minority communities. He then moved back to Long Island and resumed work at Sullivan & Cromwell, where he was involved in a large number of international corporate cases and traveled widely. In 1969 he was asked to be involved in an investigation of the My Lai massacre and filed the report which ended up being the impetus for bringing charges against a number of soldiers for their actions in Vietnam. He and his assistant were the only civilians involved in the investigation. He was living on Long Island with his wife when the interview occurred in 2007. Robert MacCrate and his wife Constance both died in 2016, and were survived by three children. Additional biographical details can be found in notes of other interviews with MacCrate.
    In this second of four interviews, Robert MacCrate discusses his time as general counsel to Nelson Rockefeller. He spends much of this section discussing his role in the re-structuring of the public higher education system in New York State. He also talks about his role in reorganizing the court system in the state. He provides insight into the politicking and importance of compromise that is integral to government. MacCrate then moves into a discussion about the history of Sullivan & Cromwell. He recalls his role in investigating the My Lai massacre in Vietnam. He details how he was contacted by the Army, and the background of My Lai. He talks about the trip he took to Vietnam, and the process of the investigation itself as well as the report he published and its repercussions. Within the final hour, MacCrate reads a lengthy speech, first delivered in 1971, about My Lai and his views on war. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Courts -- New York (State); Education, Higher |z New York (State); Governors |z New York (State); Law firms |z New York (State) |z New York; Lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York; Long Island (N.Y.); My Lai Massacre, Vietnam, 1968; New York (State) |x Politics and government; Soldiers |z United States; Vietnam War, 1961-1975
  - MacCrate, Robert, 2007 March 27; 2008.031.3.005
    Robert MacCrate was born in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1921. He attended elementary and high school at Brooklyn Friends School, and then moved on to Haverford College. After his time at Haverford, he served during wartime in the Navy. With a degree from Harvard Law, he got a job at Sullivan and Cromwell in New York, and moved to Long Island. Beginning 1958 he worked as counsel to Governor Rockefeller until 1962. During this time he was heavily involved in redrawing a number of congressional district borders in New York City in order to increase representation for minority communities. He then resumed work at Sullivan & Cromwell, where he was involved in a large number of international corporate cases and traveled widely. He was living on Long Island with his wife when the interview occurred in 2007. Robert MacCrate and his wife Constance both died in 2016, and were survived by three children. Additional biographical details can be found in notes of other interviews with MacCrate.
    In this third of four interviews, Robert MacCrate focuses on his relationship with/life in Brooklyn. He begins with reminiscing about his family life and his children. MacCrate recalls his own childhood, talking about public transportation he used to take to get to school and then moving into a discussion of New York's subways. Next, he talks about his role in redrawing congressional districts in New York City after 1960's census. He describes how his new borders stressed community representation. He launches into a discussion of baseball in Brooklyn. He recollects his childhood as a fan of the Dodgers and his efforts in government work to deed Queens parkland to create Shea Stadium. MacCrate then moves into a philosophical speech about of the role of law in society, and how he has an untenable faith in idealism. From here he talks for quite some time about his time in school. He mentions the cultural characteristics of Greenpoint when he was little. This moves him into a discussion about the different ethnic neighborhoods in Brooklyn and Manhattan. MacCrate ends by recounting a trip he took to Washington when Roosevelt declared war in 1941. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Baseball |z New York (State) |z New York; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Family life; Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York; Local transit |z New York (State) |z New York; New York (N.Y.); New York (State) |x Politics and government; United States |x Social policy |x History |y 20th century; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn Dodgers (Baseball team)
  - MacCrate, Robert, 2007 April 12; 2008.031.3.006